Sadisha Galappatti

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · CSM, SECURITY ENTHUSIAST

□ (+1) 289-339-2717 | Sadishag@gmail.com | # www.sadishagalappatti.ca | • sadishag | • sadishag

Summary_

Software Engineer in Training currently working at Manulife in a Product Development capacity. 2+ years of work experience with backend/infrastructure, web development and security and experience being a tech lead in a small team. I know my way around a unix like terminal and love to build out my perfect development environment. The hard challenges keep me motivated and moving forward. Constantly on the search for opportunities to grow personally and professionally.

SKILLS: Python, Java, NodeJS, React, Angular, Kubernetes, Ansible, Bash, HTML/CSS, Golang, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Redis, Cassandra, Postgres, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Apigee, PCF

Work Experience _____

Manulife Toronto, Canada

FULL STACK CLOUD ENGINEER

October 2021 - Present

- Developed and maintained some evaluation tooling for Manulife University
- · Leading the Azure Kubernetes Service program as primary instructor as part of Manulife University offering
- · Mentor engineers of all levels on various topics related to Software Engineering and Cloud (in Azure) across the org
- · Developing the strategy to move all offerings into Azure Kubernetes Service as part of company initiative

Manulife Toronto, Canada

ASSOCIATE FULL STACK ENGINEER

July 2019 - October 2021

- · Designed and developed product line in Individual Insurance for Insurance Advisors and customers
- Implemented micro-service architecture in Nodejs with front end built with React
- Pipelines implemented using Jenkins, Concourse with code analysis, scanning using Sonarqube

RBC Toronto, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

June 2017 - July 2019

- Architected and deployed the API Gateway platform within a time period of 4 months (https://developer.rbc.com)
- Ensured full scalability and security of the platform during implementation and automated operational/CI/CD tasks using Ansible, Jenkins, Python and Github
- Improved turnaround time to engage and integrate external partnerships for the entire bank by 50%
- Managed and maintained the infrastructure to run the API Gateway platform to allow for a 99.99% up time SLA and lead the push for an in production zero downtime upgrade of the platform
- Enabled Oauth and Mutual Authenticaion (2waySSL) as generic policy to add to API's. Policies are now used in 300+ API's at RBC
- Contributor to various internal open-source (innersource) projects at RBC
- KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: RBC Digital Q3 2018 Team Award, Top Performance Rating for 2 years in a row

Blackberry Limited Waterloo, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Built restful API's (Ruby on Rails) following a microservice architecture as part of a 2.0 deployment of BlackBerry CloudConsole application
- Dashboard development such as chargeback data pull, OS level patch monitoring, KAFKA/GRAFANA integration
- Developed on top of an asset tracking configuration management platform

Program Committees

2013 - Pres Technical/Youth Board Member, Wellwood Cancer Centre

Hamilton, Canada

Education

McMaster University

Hamilton, Canada

B.Eng. in Software Engineering Class of 2017

JUNE 6, 2022 SADISHA GALAPPATTI · RÉSUMÉ 1